Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Correspondence - subject files
  - Josephs, Laurence. Cold Water Morning, 1963 (Box 30)
  - Josephson, Ben (Box 30)
  - Joughin, G. Louis (Box 30)
  - Journal of Higher Education (Box 30)
  - Joy, Charles Rhind (Box 30)
  - Joyce, James (Box 30)
  - Jubilee (Box 30)
  - K (Box 30)
  - Kadushin, Charles (Box 30)
  - Kalechofsky, Roberta (Box 30)
  - Kallich, Martin (Box 30)
  - Kallman, Elizabeth, See Wheelock, Elizabeth.
  - Kane, Joseph (Box 30)
  - Kapelner, Alan (Box 30)
  - Kaplan, Harold (Box 30)
  - Kaswan, Ruth Siler (Box 30)
  - Katz, Leslie (Box 30)
  - Katz, Shlomo (Box 30)
  - Kauffmann, Stanley (Box 30)
  - Kay, Ulysses (Box 30)
  - Kazin, Alfred (Box 30)
  - Keating, George T. (Box 30)
  - Keedick, Lee (Box 30)
  - Keenan, James F. (Box 30)
  - Kelley, Sally (Box 30)
  - Kelsey, William Kline (Box 30)
  - Kempton, Murray (Box 30)
  - Kendall, Paul Murray and family, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Kenderdine, John D. (Box 30)
  - Kennedy, William (Box 30)
  - Kent, Rockwell (Box 30)
  - Kenton, Edna (Box 30)
  - Kenyon Review (Box 30)
  - Kepler, Thomas Samuel (Box 30)
  - Kerkhoff, Johnston D. (Box 30)
  - Kern, Alfred (Box 30)
  - Kern, John Dwight (Box 30)
  - Ketchum, Richard M. (Box 30)
  - Kienitz, John Fabian (Box 30)
  - Kieran, John (Box 30)
  - Kiley, Frederick T. (Box 30)
  - Killinger, John (Box 30)
  - Kincead, Beatrice (Box 30)
  - King, Grace (Box 30)
  - Kingsley, Charles (Box 31)
  - Kingsley, John Donald (Box 31)
  - Kinnamon, Keneth (Box 31)
  - Kipling, Rudyard (Box 31)
  - Kirchwey, Freda (Box 31)
  - Kirkland, Joseph (Box 31)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln (Box 31)
  - Kitay, Geraldine (Box 31)
  - Kizer, Carolyn (Box 31)
  - Klein, Alexander (Box 31)
  - Klein, Herbert Arthur (Box 31)
  - Klinke, H.O. (Box 31)
  - Kluger, Richard (Box 31)
  - Knickerbocker, Charles H. (Box 31)
  - Knickerbocker, William S. (Box 31)
  - Knight, Damon (Box 31)
  - Knight, Eric (Box 31)
  - Knight, Grant Cochran (Box 31)
  - Knight, Jere (Mrs. Eric) (Box 31)
  - Knoll, Robert E. (Box 31)
  - Knopf, (Alfred A.), Inc. (Box 31)
  - Koestler, Arthur (Box 31)
  - Kogan, Herman (Box 31)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred (Box 31)
  - Kohn, David (Box 31)
  - Kohner, Frederick (Box 31)
  - Kolb, Harold H. (Box 31)
  - Konecky, Edith (Box 31)
  - Konecky, Eugene (Box 31)
  - Kosinski, Jerzy (Box 31)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard (Box 31)
  - Kramer, Dale (Box 31)
  - Kramer, Eugene F. (Box 31)
  - Kraus, Harry P. (Box 31)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred (Box 31)
  - Kristol, Irving (Box 31)
  - Kronenberger, Louis (Box 31)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 31)
  - Kuenstler, Frank (Box 31)
  - Kuh, Katharine (Box 31)
  - Kunitz, Joshua (Box 31)
  - Kuo, Ching-ch'iu, See Kuo, Helena.
  - Kuo, Helena (Box 31)
  - L (Box 31)
  - Labor Research Association (Box 31)
  - LaFlamme, Gladys (Box 31)
  - Lahey, Edwin A. (Box 31)
  - LaHood, Marvin J. (Box 31)
  - Lamb, Edward (Box 31)
  - Lamb, Robert K., 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1934-1965; undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Lancaster, Elizabeth G. (Box 32)
    See also Wheelock, Elizabeth.
  - Landis, James McCauley (Box 32)
  - Lane, Alfred Church (Box 32)
  - Lang, Harry, See Lang, Lucy Robins.
  - Lang, Lucy Robins, 1911-1958; undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Langer, Elinor (Box 32)
  - Langford, Richard E. (Box 32)
  - Langley, Christopher (Box 32)
  - Lania, Leo (Box 32)
  - Lanier, Henry W. (Box 32)
  - Lankes, Julius J. (Box 32)
  - Lanning, George (Box 32)
  - Lape, Fred (Box 32)
  - Larkin, Oliver W. (Box 32)
  - Larremore, Thomas (Box 32)
  - Lash, Joseph P. (Box 32)
  - Lasker, Bruno (Box 32)
  - Laski, Harold J. (Box 32)
  - Lasky, Melvin J. (Box 32)
    See also Der Monat.
  - Lasky, Victor (Box 32)
  - Latham, Harold (Box 32)
    See also Macmillan Co..
  - Laughlin, James (Box 32)
  - Lauterbach, Albert T. (Box 32)
  - Lawrence, David Herbert (Box 32)
  - Lawrence, James Cooper (Box 32)
  - Lawrence, Seymour (Box 32)
  - Lawson, John Howard (Box 32)
  - Lawson, Robert Wilde (Box 32)
  - Layton, Roland Vanderbilt (Box 32)
  - Lazo, Hector (Box 32)
  - Lea, James W. (Box 32)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard (Box 32)
  - League for American Ideals (Box 32)
  - League for Industrial Democracy (Box 32)
  - League of American Writers, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - League of Women Voters of Albany County (Box 33)
  - Leary, Lewis Gaston (Box 33)
  - Lechlitner, Ruth (Box 33)
  - Lee, Audrey (Box 33)
  - Lee, Charles (Box 33)
  - Lee, Clarence Pendleton (Box 33)
  - Lee, Harry 0. (Box 33)
  - Leeds, Barry H. (Box 33)
  - Leekley, Richard (Box 33)
  - Left Front (Box 33)
  - Left Review (Box 33)
  - Lehan, Richard Daniel (Box 33)
  - Lehr, Wilson (Box 33)
  - Leites, Nathan. "Trends in Moral Temper", 1947 (Box 33)
  - Lemon, Lee T. (Box 33)
  - Lentin, Albert Paul (Box 33)
  - Leonard, Dorothy (Box 33)
  - Lermond, Norman Wallace (Box 33)
  - Lerner, Max (Box 33)
  - Lerner, Tillie (Box 33)
  - Lester, Bernard (Box 33)
  - Levenson, Leah, 1938-1966; undated; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Levenson, Samuel, 1932-1970; undated; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Levine, Paul (Box 33)
  - Levinson, Burton E. (Box 33)
  - Levitas, Sol (Box 33)
  - Levitov, Aleksandr Ivanovich (Box 33)
  - Levoy, Myron (Box 33)
  - Levy, Melvin P. (Box 33)
  - Lewis, Alfred Henry (Box 33)
  - Lewis, H.H. (Box 33)
  - Lewis, Harold M.J. (Box 33)
  - Lewis, James Franklin (Box 33)
  - Lewis, Joseph (Box 33)
    See also Freethinkers of America.
  - Lewis, Leon (Box 33)
  - Lewis, Richard J. (Box 34)
  - Lewis, Richard Warrington Baldwin (Box 34)
  - Lewis, Sinclair (Box 34)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig (Box 34)
  - Liberation (Box 34)
  - Liberty Presbyterian Church forum (Box 34)
  - Library of Congress (Box 34)
  - Lid, Richard Wald (Box 34)
  - Lieber, Maxim (Box 34)
  - Lieder, Paul Robert (Box 34)
  - Life (Box 34)
  - Lilienthal, David E., See Tennessee Valley Authority.
  - Lillibridge, George D. (Don), 1950-1966; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Limited Editions Club (Box 34)
  - Lindell, Richard Leonard (Box 34)
  - Linet, Henry A. (Box 34)
  - Linney, Romulus (Box 34)
  - J. B. Lippincott Company (Box 34)
  - Lippmann, Walter (Box 34)
  - Literary Guild of America, Inc. (Box 34)
  - Literary Horizons, pre-publication miscellany (Box 34)
  - Literature (Box 34)
  - Littell, Robert (Box 34)
  - Little, Bertram K. (Box 34)
  - Little, Brown & Company (Box 34)
  - Liveright (Box 34)
  - The Living Novel, 1956-1957; undated; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Lloyd, William Bross (Box 34)
  - Locke, Octavia, 1956-1971; undated; 4 folders (Box 35)
  - Loeb, Harold (Box 35)
  - London, Jack (Box 35)
  - Long Island University. Southampton College (Box 35)
  - Longmans, Green & Company (Box 35)
  - Loomis, Edward (Box 35)
  - Loomis, Mildred Jensen (Box 35)
  - Lorimer, George Horace (Box 35)
  - Lothar, Ernst (Box 35)
  - Lott, Milton (Mrs.) (Box 35)
  - Louisiana State University Press (Box 35)
  - Louisville, University of (Box 35)
  - Loveland, Constance (Box 35)
  - Lovestone, Jay (Box 35)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss (Box 35)
  - Loving, Pierre (Box 35)
  - Lowe, Robert Liddell (Box 35)
  - Lowell, James Russell (Box 35)
  - Lowell, Robert (Box 35)
  - Lowenfels, Walter (Box 35)
  - Lowenthal, Leo (Box 35)
  - Lowry, Margerie (Box 35)
  - Lowry, Malcolm (Box 35)
    See also Lowry, Margerie.
  - Luce, Henry (Box 35)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge (Box 35)
  - Lund, Herbert F. (Box 35)
  - Lundahl, Gene (Box 35)
  - Lurie, David (Box 35)
  - Lutz, Alma (Box 35)
  - Lydenburg, John, 1939-1968; undated; 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Lynd, Helen (Merrell) (Box 35)
  - Lynes, Russell (Box 35)
  - Lynn, Kenneth S. "Authors in Search of the Businessman." Harvard Business Review, undated (Box 35)
  - Lyon, Don W. (and Dot) (Box 36)
  - Lyon, Peter (Box 36)
  - Lyons, Eugene (Box 36)
  - Lyons, Louis Martin (Box 36)
  - M (Box 36)
  - MacAlpine, Eadmonn (Box 36)
  - Macaulay, Thomas Babington (Box 36)
  - Robert M. McBride & Company (Box 36)
  - MacCampbell, Donald (Box 36)
  - McCarthy, Mary (Box 36)
  - McConkey, James (Box 36)
  - McConnell, William C. (Box 36)
  - McCormick, Kenneth Dale (Box 36)
  - McCoy, Samuel Duff (Box 36)
  - McCullers, Carson (Box 36)
  - McCullough, Dan H. (Box 36)
  - McCurtin, Peter (Box 36)
  - McDaniel, Thomas R. (Box 36)
  - Macdonald, Dwight (Box 36)
  - MacDougall, William R. (Box 36)
  - McDowell, Tremaine (Box 36)
  - McGee, Alan vol. (Box 36)
  - MacGillivray, Arthur (Box 36)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company (Box 36)
  - McGuane, Thomas (Box 36)
  - McHugh, Vincent (Box 36)
  - Macias, Anna (Box 36)
  - MacInnes, Helen (Box 36)
  - McIntire, Marguerite (Pearman) (Box 36)
  - Mack, Tom (Box 36)
  - David McKay Company, Inc. (Box 36)
  - MacKaye, Percy (Box 36)
  - McKinley, Georgia, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - McKinney, Laurence (Box 36)
  - Macklin, F.A. (Box 36)
  - McLaughlin, David (Box 36)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 36)
  - MacLennan, Hugh (Box 36)
  - Macmillan Company, 1926-1933; 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Macmillan Company, 1934-1947; 12 folders (Box 37)
  - Macmillan Company, 1948-1967; 12 folders (Box 38)
  - McMurry, Donald L. (Box 38)
  - McNamara, Edward T. (Box 38)
  - McNamee, Lawrence Francis (Box 38)
  - McNerney, Eugene A. (Box 38)
  - McNutt, Paul vol. (Box 38)
  - MacShane, Frank (Box 38)
  - McWilliams, Carey (Box 38)
  - Macy, Helen (Box 38)
  - Madden, David, 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Madison, Charles Allan (Box 39)
  - Magil, Abraham Bernard (Box 39)
  - Maher, Constance Loveland, See Loveland, Constance.
  - Mailer, Norman (Box 39)
  - Malamud, Bernard, 3 folders (Box 39)
  - Mallock, William Hurrell (Box 39)
  - Malone, Dumas, See also Dictionary of American Biography. (Box 39)
  - Maltz, Albert (Box 39)
  - Malzberg, Barry N. (Box 39)
  - Manchester, William Raymond (Box 39)
  - Manfred, Ernest Fred (Box 39)
  - Manfred, Frederick (Box 39)
  - Manfred, Freya (Box 39)
  - Mangione, Jerre Gerlando (Box 39)
  - The Manitoban (Box 39)
  - Manneslied, Claire (Box 39)
  - Manning, Stanley (Box 39)
  - Mannix, Edward (Box 39)
  - Manny, Frank A. (Box 39)
  - Mansfield, Luther Stearns (Box 39)
  - Mantle, Burns (Box 39)
  - Marberry, Virginia Gardner, See Gardner, Virginia.
  - March, William (Box 39)
  - Marcosson, Isaac Frederick (Box 39)
  - Marcus, Alan (Box 39)
  - Margolies, Edward (Box 39)
  - Marquand, John P. (Box 39)
  - Marquette University (Box 39)
  - Martin, Edward Sanford (Box 39)
  - Martin, Jay (Box 39)
  - Martineau, Harriet (Box 39)
  - Marvin, Dwight (Box 39)
  - Marx, Leo (Box 39)
  - Marxist study group (Box 39)
  - Marxist Symposium, study of American culture (Box 39)
  - Mary Ethel, Sister (Box 39)
  - Masefield, John (Box 39)
  - Mason, Daniel Gregory (Box 39)
  - Mason, Ruth (Box 39)
  - Massachusetts Review (Box 39)
  - Masses - Contempo, April 5, 1933 (Box 39)
  - Massing, Hede (Box 39)
  - Massing, Paul W. (Box 39)
  - Masters, Dexter (Box 39)
  - Masters, Hilary (Box 39)
  - Matthews, Jack (Box 40)
  - Matthiessen, Francis Otto (Box 40)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset (Box 40)
  - Maule, Harry Edward (Box 40)
  - Maxwell, William (Box 40)
  - May, Elizabeth Stoffregen (Box 40)
  - Mayberry, George (Box 40)
  - Mayfield, Sara (Box 40)
  - Meanjin (Box 40)
  - Meck, John Foster (Box 40)
  - Meech, Sanford B. (Box 40)
  - Meller, Sidney (Box 40)
  - Mellquist, Jerome (Box 40)
  - Meltzer, Francoise Claire (Box 40)
  - Meltzer, Milton (Box 40)
  - Melville, Herman (Box 40)
  - Memoirs (Box 40)
  - Mencken, H.L. (Box 40)
  - Mendelson, Harry G. (Box 40)
  - Meredith, George (Box 40)
  - Meridian Books (Box 40)
  - Merriam, Eve (Box 40)
  - Merton, Robert K. (Box 40)
  - Metcalfe, John (Box 40)
  - Meyer, Andrew (Box 40)
  - Meyer, Frank S. (Box 40)
  - Meyer, Karl Ernest (Box 40)
  - Michelson, Herman (Box 40)
  - Michener, James A. (Box 40)
  - Middlebury College (Box 40)
  - Middlebury Conference (Box 40)
  - Middleton, William Vernon (Box 40)
  - Midstream (Box 40)
  - Milano, Paolo (Box 40)
  - Miles, Mildred Lynn (Box 40)
  - Milgram, Morris (Box 40)
  - Mill, John Stuart (Box 40)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent (Box 40)
  - Miller, Arthur (Box 40)
  - Miller, Fred R. (Box 40)
  - Miller, Harlan (Box 40)
  - Miller, James Edwin (Box 40)
  - Miller, Merle (Box 40)
  - Miller, Nolan (Box 40)
  - Miller, Perry (Box 40)
  - Miller, Russ (Box 40)
  - Mills, C. Wright (Box 40)
  - Mills, Ralph J. (Box 40)
  - Milwaukee Journal (Box 40)
  - Mims, Helen (Sullivan) (Box 40)
  - Minnesota, University of. University Press (Box 40)
  - Minor, Lydia Gibson (Box 40)
  - Mirabelli, Eugene (Box 40)
  - Mishory, Mark (Box 40)
  - Mitchell, Broadus (Box 40)
  - Mitchell, Louise Pearson (Box 40)
  - Mitchell, Margaret (Box 40)
  - Mitchell, Robert A. (Box 40)
  - Mitchison, Naomi (Haldane) (Box 40)
  - Modern Age Books, 1937-1942; undated; 5 folders (Box 41)
  - Modern Age Books - Reader's reports (Box 41)
  - Modern Language Association (Box 41)
  - Modern Review (Box 41)
  - Modern Socialism (Box 41)
  - Moffett, Judith (Box 41)
  - Mok, Paul P. (Box 41)
  - Der Monat (Box 41)
  - Monsarrat, Nicholas (Box 41)
  - Montague, Charles Edward (Box 41)
  - Montana Study, See Brownell, Baker.
  - Montgomery, Richard Gill (Box 41)
  - Mood, Fulmer, 1930-1965; 4 folders (Box 41)
  - Moody, William Vaughan (Box 41)
  - Moon, Bucklin (Box 41)
  - Moore, Brian (Box 41)
  - Moore, George (Box 41)
  - Moore, Harry Thornton (Box 41)
  - Moore, John G. (Box 41)
  - Moores, Richard Gordon (Box 41)
  - Mordell, Albert (Box 41)
  - Morgan, Arthur Ernest (Box 41)
  - Morgan, Griscom. Vitality and Civilization, 1947 (Box 41)
  - Morgan, Carole (Box 41)
  - Morgan, Frederick (Box 41)
  - Morgan, Maud (Box 41)
  - Morressy, John (Box 41)
  - Morrill, George (Box 41)
  - Morris, Benjamin Wistar (Box 41)
  - Morris, Dorothy (and Charles) (Box 41)
  - Morris, Walter Ripton, 1936-1971; undated; 4 folders (Box 42)
  - Morris, William (Box 42)
  - Morris (William) Agency, See William Morris Agency.
  - Morris, Wright, 8 folders (Box 42)
  - Morrison, Arthur (Box 43)
  - Morrison, Theodore (Box 43)
  - Morrow, Donald (Box 43)
  - Morrow, Felix (Box 43)
  - William Morrow & Co., Inc. (Box 43)
  - Morse, Josiah Mitchell (Box 43)
  - Morse, Stearns (Box 43)
  - Mote, Carl Henry (Box 43)
  - Mottram, Ralph Hale (Box 43)
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott (Box 43)
  - Moynahan, James H.S. (Box 43)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 43)
  - Mundus Artium (Box 43)
  - Munroe, James Phinney (Box 43)
  - Munson, Gorham Bert (Box 43)
  - Murdoch, Iris (Box 43)
  - Murdock, Kenneth Ballard (Box 43)
  - Mussey, June Barrows (Box 43)
  - Muste, Abraham John (Box 43)
  - N (Box 43)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir (Box 43)
  - Nadig, Henry Davis (Box 43)
  - Nagel, James (Box 43)
  - Nahm, Milton Charles (Box 43)
  - Nankivell, Frank Arthur (Box 43)
  - Nason, Leonard (Box 43)
  - Nathan, Paul S. (Box 43)
  - Nathan, Robert Louis (Box 43)
  - The Nation (Box 43)
  - The National Book Award, 1951-1959 (Box 43)
  - The National Book Committee, 1965-1973; undated; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - National Broadcasting Company. NBC University Theatre (Box 43)
  - National Committee for People's Rights (Box 43)
  - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners (Box 43)
  - National Conference on the Community (Box 44)
  - National Council of Teachers of English (Box 44)
  - National Education Association (Box 44)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Box 44)
  - National Writers Club (Box 44)
  - Nearing, Helen K. (Box 44)
  - Nearing, Scott (Box 44)
  - Nebraska Library Association (Box 44)
  - Neider, Charles (Box 44)
  - Neiman, Gilbert (Box 44)
  - Nelson, John Truman (Box 44)
  - Neufeld, John (Box 44)
  - Neumann, Henry (Box 44)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 44)
  - Nevius, Blake (Box 44)
  - New America (Box 44)
  - New American Library (Box 44)
  - New Directions (publisher) (Box 44)
  - New England Historic Genealogical Society (Box 44)
  - New England Town Hall, Inc. (Box 44)
  - The New Freeman (Box 44)
  - New Frontier (Box 44)
  - New Hampshire (State) (Box 44)
  - New International Year Book, See Funk and Wagnalls Company.
  - The New Leader, 1942-1972; undated; 2 folders (Box 44)
  - The New Leader, New Yorker book reviews article (Box 44)
  - New Letters in America (Box 44)
  - New Masses, 1932-1939; undated; 3 folders (Box 44)
  - New Masses, Reviewers (Box 44)
  - The New Republic, 1925-1975; undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - New School for Social Research, 1955-1964; undated; 7 folders (Box 45)
  - The New South (Box 45)
  - New Writing (Box 45)
  - The New York Evening Post (Box 45)
  - New York Herald Tribune (Box 45)
  - New York Post (Box 45)
  - New York Public Library (Box 45)
  - New York State Education (Box 45)
  - New York State history (Box 45)
  - New York Times Book Review (Box 45)
  - New York University (Box 45)
  - New York University Press (Box 45)
  - The New Yorker (Box 46)
  - Newcomb, Theodore (Box 46)
  - Newdick, Robert S. (Box 46)
  - Newhouse, Edward (Box 46)
  - Newland Press (Box 46)
  - Newman, Albert M. (Box 46)
  - Newsday (Box 46)
  - Nichols, Acosta (Box 46)
  - Niemeyer, Carl Anthony (Box 46)
  - Nock, Albert Jay (Box 46)
  - Nomad, Max (Box 46)
  - Norman, Charles (Box 46)
  - Norris, Frank (Box 46)
  - North, Joseph (Box 46)
  - North Carolina State College (Box 46)
  - Northshield, Jane (Box 46)
  - Northwest Review (Box 46)
  - Northwestern University (Box 46)
  - Norton, Clement A. (Box 46)
  - W.W. Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 46)
  - Norway, Nevil Shute, See Shute, Nevil.
  - Norwick, Braham, 1935-1965; undated; 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Noth, Ernst Erich (Box 46)
  - Notre Dame, University of (Box 46)
  - Nuhn, Ferner (Box 46)
  - Nyren, Dorothy (Box 46)
  - O (Box 46)
  - Oak, Liston M. (Box 46)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Obscenity (Box 46)
  - O'Casey, Sean (Box 46)
  - O'Connell, Thomas Edward (Box 46)
  - O'Connor, Flannery, 4 folders (Box 47)
  - O'Connor, Harvey (Box 47)
  - O'Connor, William Van (Box 47)
  - Odets, Clifford (Box 47)
  - Odum, Howard Washington (Box 47)
  - Odyssey Press, Inc. (Box 47)
  - O'Hara, John (Box 47)
  - Ohio University (Box 47)
  - Ohio Valley Writers' Conference (Box 47)
  - Olivet College (Box 47)
  - O'Neill, Eugene (Box 47)
  - Only One Storm, Feb. 1942-1949; undated; 3 folders (Box 47)
  - Onward (Box 47)
  - Orton, William Aylott (Box 47)
  - Orwell, George (Box 47)
  - O'Sullivan, Vincent. The Good Girl (Box 47)
  - Otis, Brooks (Box 47)
  - Otto Rank Association (Box 47)
  - Overstreet, Harry Allen (Box 47)
  - Overton, Richard Cleghorn (Box 47)
  - Owen, Bert B. (Box 47)
  - Owen, Guy (Box 47)
  - Oxford University Press (Box 47)
  - P (Box 47)
  - Pacific Northwest Writers Conference (Box 48)
  - Padgette, Paul (Box 48)
  - Page, Charles Hunt (Box 48)
  - Page, Dorothy Myra (Box 48)
  - Page, Myra, See Page, Dorothy Myra.
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (Box 48)
  - Painter, Charlotte (Box 48)
  - Palamountain, Joseph C. (Box 48)
  - Paperback Review (Box 48)
  - Parker, Hershel (Box 48)
  - Parrington, Vernon Louis (Box 48)
  - Parry, Albert (Box 48)
  - "The Parsons and the War", 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Part of the Truth, 1965-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Partisan Review (Box 48)
  - Patchen, Kenneth (Box 48)
  - Pathfinder (Box 48)
  - Patmore, Coventry (Box 48)
  - Patton, Julia (Box 48)
  - Payne, Lucile Vaughan (Box 48)
  - Pearl, Jeannette D. (Box 48)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes (Box 48)
  - Pearson, Ralph Emerson (Box 48)
  - Peck, Gustav (Box 48)
  - Peden, William (Box 48)
  - Peirce, Waldo (Box 48)
  - P. E. N. (Box 48)
  - Pendrell, Ernest (Box 48)
  - Pennington, Leslie T. (Box 48)
  - Pennycock, Andrew (Box 48)
  - Pennsylvania State University (Box 48)
  - Pennsylvania, University of (Box 48)
  - People's Institute of Applied Religion (Box 48)
  - Percy, Walker (Box 48)
  - Perky, Cheves West (Box 48)
  - Perry, Kathleen R. (Box 48)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton (Box 48)
    See also Dennison job - summer 1923 (II).
  - Peterson, Don (Box 48)
  - Peterson, Edwin Lewis (Box 48)
  - Petrakis, Harry Mark (Box 48)
  - Pew, Marlen Edwin (Box 48)
  - Pfeiffer, Karl G. (Box 48)
  - Phelps, Wallace (Box 48)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance (Box 48)
  - Philipson, Morris (Box 48)
  - Philipson, Morris. Paradoxes, 1968 (Box 48)
  - Phillips, David Graham, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Phillips, John Sanburn (Box 49)
  - Phillips, Robert S. (Box 49)
  - Picard, Jacob (Box 49)
  - Pilat, Oliver Ramsay (Box 49)
  - Pinchon, Edgcumb (Box 49)
  - Pinchot, Amos R.E. (Box 49)
  - Pino, Austin L. (Box 49)
  - Pinska, Stanley (Box 49)
  - Plain Talk (Box 49)
  - Podhoretz, Norman (Box 49)
  - Poetry (Box 49)
  - Politics (Box 49)
  - Polk, Noel Earl (Box 49)
  - Pollans, Bertrand E. (Box 49)
  - Poller, Rebekah, 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Poole, Ernest (Box 49)
  - Pooley, Robert Cecil (Box 49)
  - Porter, William Sydney (Box 49)
  - Portner, Stuart (Box 49)
  - Potter, Grace Elizabeth (Box 49)
  - Potter, Nancy A.J. (Box 49)
  - Pound, Ezra (Box 49)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton (Box 49)
  - Powell, Anthony (Box 49)
  - Pressly, Thomas J. (Box 49)
  - Preston, John Hyde (Box 49)
  - Price, Don K. "Purists and Politicians", 1969 (Box 49)
  - Price, Ellen, See Mary Ethel, Sister.
  - Price, Lucien (Box 49)
  - Price, Reynolds (Box 49)
  - Priestley, John Boynton (Box 49)
  - Princeton University (Box 49)
  - Princeton University Press (Box 49)
  - Princetonian (Box 49)
  - Pritchard, Katharine Susannah (Box 49)
  - Progressive Book Club (Box 49)
  - Prokosch, Frederic (Box 49)
  - Proletarian Literature in the United States, 1935 (Box 49)
  - Pross, Helge (Box 49)
  - Proust, Marcel (Box 49)
  - Psychology (Box 49)
  - Puerto Rico, University of (Box 49)
  - Purdy, James (Box 49)
  - Putnam, Emily James (Smith) (Box 49)
  - Putnam, James (Box 49)
  - [G. P.] Putnam's, 3 folders (Box 49)
  - [G. P.] Putnam's, 1939-1973; reader's reports (Box 49)
  - Putney School (Box 50)
  - Q (Box 50)
  - Quadrangle Books (Box 50)
  - Quinn, John J. (Box 50)
  - R (Box 50)
  - RPI General correspondence (Box 50)
  - RPI Convocation, Church and Work Congress, 1955 (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, American Association of University Professors (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, American Civil Liberties Union (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, clippings (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, letters of support (Box 50)
  - RPI dismissal, miscellany (Box 50)
  - Radio (Box 50)
  - Radley, Virginia L. (Box 50)
  - Rahv, Philip (Box 50)
  - Raible, Robert (Box 50)
  - Raines, Halsey (Box 50)
  - Rame, David (Box 50)
  - Random House, Inc. (Box 50)
  - Random House Dictionary of the English Language (Box 50)
  - Ransome, Arthur (Box 50)
  - Rathburn, Robert Charles (Box 50)
  - Read, Opie Percival (Box 50)
  - Reade, Leslie (Box 50)
  - Reagan, Michael D. (Box 50)
  - Recht, Charles (Box 50)
  - Rechy, John (Box 50)
  - Record, Wilson (Box 51)
  - Red Sparks (Box 51)
  - Redding, Jay Saunders (Box 51)
  - Redford, Grant H. (Box 51)
  - Redpath Bureau (Box 51)
  - John Reed Club (Box 51)
  - Regent, Albert (Box 51)
  - Regier, Cornelius C. The Era of the Muckrackers. (Box 51)
  - Regional planning (Box 51)
  - Regionalism (Box 51)
  - Reinstein, Herman (Box 51)
  - Reissig, Herman Frederick (Box 51)
  - Renault, Mary (Box 51)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, See RPI.
  - The Reporter (Box 51)
  - Resignation from Communist Party, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Reuben, William A. (Box 51)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth (Box 51)
  - Rezneck, Samuel (Box 51)
  - Rich, Louis (Box 51)
  - Richards, Ivor Armstrong (Box 51)
  - Richardson, Henry Handel (Box 51)
  - Richler, Mordecai (Box 51)
  - Richter, Conrad (Box 51)
  - Rickword, Edgell (Box 51)
  - Rideout, Walter Bates (Box 51)
  - Riemer, Svend (Box 51)
  - Riesman, David (Box 51)
  - Riess, Curt (Box 51)
  - Riggs, Strafford (Box 51)
  - Rinehart and Company, Inc. (Box 51)
  - Ritchey, R.H. (Box 51)
  - Ritt, Martin (Box 51)